Contact

senarathnesakitha2@gmail.co

www.linkedin.com/in/sakithasenarathne (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Modeling
Applied Statistics
Feature Engineering

Sakitha Senarathne

Data Science and Business Intelligence Enthusiast. Sri Lanka

Summary

Experienced Business Intelligence Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Data Visualization, Data Analysis, R, Statistics, and Python (Programming Language). Strong administrative professional with a Bachelor of Science - BS focused in Applied Statistics from University of Colombo.

Experience

Insharp Technologies (Private)Limited Associate Business Intelligence Engineer May 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month) Sri Lanka

Develop data pipelines to extract, transform, and load data using SQL and Python.

Contribute in the full BI development life cycle from scoping, analysis, design, implementation, and quality assurance to delivery and support.

Participate in business process analysis and requirements gathering sessions with business stakeholders.

R&D with PDF data mining in the context of NLP and ML.

airtel

Management Information System Executive May 2018 - February 2019 (10 months) Sri Lanka

Develop logic, build from scratch and maintain analytical reports (both ad-hoc and scheduled) using SQL, Excel, Access programs.

Develop SQL code and VBA macros to automate and improve efficiencies, quality, and timeliness of current routine reports and processes.

Education

University of Colombo

Bachelor of Science - BS, Industrial Statistics and Financial Mathematics · (2014 - 2017)

DS Senanayake College

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry · (2011 - 2013)